# **David Williams**

### **David Williams**

Apartment 54 7 Tiltman Place London N7 7EL

+447432104037 dave@dave.io

Please note: due to disability, I am exclusively seeking a remote role.

# **Skills**

Motivated, qualified, and experienced multiplatform infrastructure engineer, specialising in Debian and Red Hat based Linux environments, but equally comfortable in Windows.

Experienced with Linux, \*BSD, and various network appliance operating systems such as IOS, Vyatta, MikroTik, Ubiquiti, and Juniper.

Comfortable and experienced with various virtualisation / 'cloud' platforms, particularly VMware and AWS.

Self-taught skills and lifelong special interest in information security, penetration testing, platform hardening, DFIR, and IoT security.

Self-taught skills with Kubernetes and Docker-based containerisation technologies.

Nonprofessional experience of electronic engineering and "making". Member of the London Hackspace since its inception.

Experienced with Go, Python, Ruby, and shellscript. Intermediate skills with Java. Limited skills with JavaScript.

Lateral and quick thinker when emergent circumstances arise.

# **Experience**

#### Mozilla / MOC Engineer (remote)

SEPTEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017, LONDON

Extremely wide-ranging role, demanding broad skillset and ability to learn new skills quickly. Management of the full Mozilla infrastructure. Communication and collaboration with widely varying teams with various focuses and technical ability. Point of contact for "I don't know who I should talk to about this, but" queries. Began development of in-house operations intelligence software ('Panopticon').

### Facebook / Production Engineer

JULY 2013 - JULY 2014, SAN FRANCISCO

Working with the Facebook storage infrastructure. Massive-scale Linux administration and toolset development, with on-call duties.

### **Six Degrees Group / Systems Administrator**

Previously **Ultraspeed** 

JULY 2009 - MAY 2013, LONDON

Part of a small team running a large Linux and Windows managed hosting estate backed on VMware. Datacentre work, on-call duties, direct contact with customers. 3PAR SAN administration. Vyatta network administration. Threat management and attack surface reduction. Design, implementation, and ongoing ownership of managed backup platform.

# ioko / Systems Administrator

JULY 2007 - JUNE 2009, LONDON AND YORK

Linux-based deployment management, toolset development, and systems support for large-scale IPTV clients. On-call work.

# **Inspired Gaming Group / Systems Administrator**

MAY 2006 - MAY 2007, LONDON

Systems administration for a mid-scale RHEL, Windows, and AIX estate. Managed migration of physical server estate to VMware virtualisation. EMC SAN administration. On-call work.

### **DXI Networks / VoIP Engineer**

FEBRUARY 2005 - APRIL 2006, LONDON

Design, implementation, and support of a country-wide VoIP network based on Cisco hardware and software. On-call work.

#### Education

#### **University of Kent** / Computer Science (BSc 2.2 Hons)

SEPTEMBER 2003 - JULY 2007, CANTERBURY

#### ITIL / ITIL Certified

FEBRUARY 2009

#### **Red Hat /** Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHEL 5)

APRIL 2007

# Keywords

3PAR, Apache, Asigra Enterprise Backup, CentOS, Cloud Computing, cPanel, Database Administration, EMC, FreeBSD, HAProxy, High Availability, IT Security, ITIL, Linux, Load Balancing, Mac OS X, MySQL, NAS, Network Administration, Network Security, Nginx, Passenger, PostgreSQL, Python, Red Hat Linux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SAN, Systems Administration, Ubuntu, VMware, Vignette, Virtualisation, Windows, Windows Server